Peirong Liu

☑ peirong@cs.unc.edu • ☎ (919)-519-8893 • ♥ peirong26

Education

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

Shanghai University

Shanghai, China B.S. in Mathematics Sep 2014 – Jun 2018

• GPA: 3.94/4.00 (Rank: 1/305); President's List (Top 10); National Scholarship (Top 1%)

Summary

My research interests broadly lie in computer vision, machine learning and medical imaging. My recent research topics include (1) Physics-informed deep learning for transport video understanding and anomaly detection; (2) Fluid-based image registration; (3) Vision transformer (ViT) based image/video object detection, open-vocabulary object detection; (4) Unsupervised motion transfer and video synthesis; (5) CT/MR perfusion imaging, lesion detection and segmentation.

Publications

Peirong Liu, Yueh Lee, Stephen Aylward, Marc Niethammer. "Deep Decomposition for Stochastic Normal-Abnormal Transport". IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2022. (Oral - 4.0%) [paper] Peirong Liu, Marc Niethammer. "Detect Anomalies from Stochastic Transport Perspective". In submission to IEEE *Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI)*, 2022.

Maxime Oquab, Daniel Haziza, Ludovic Schwartz, Katayoun Zand, Tao Xu, Peirong Liu, Rui Wang, Camille Couprie. "Efficient Conditioned Face Animation Using Frontally-viewed Embedding". Arxiv Preprint, 2022. [paper]

Peirong Liu, Rui Wang, Xuefei Cao, Yipin Zhou, Ashish Shah, Maxime Oquab, Camille Couprie, Ser-Nam Lim. "Self-appearance-aided Differential Evolution for Motion Transfer". arXiv preprint, 2021. [paper]

Peirong Liu, Lin Tian, Yubo Zhang, Stephen Aylward, Yueh Lee, Marc Niethammer. "Discovering Hidden Physics Behind Transport Dynamics". IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2021. (Oral - 3.7%) [paper]

Zhengyang Shen*, Jean Feydy*, **Peirong Liu**, Ariel Hernán Curiale, Ruben San José Estépar, Raúl San José Estépar, Marc Niethammer. "Accurate Point Cloud Registration with Robust Optimal Transport". Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2021. [paper]

Zhipeng Ding, Xu Han, Peirong Liu, Marc Niethammer. "Local Temperature Scaling for Probability Calibration". IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021. [paper]

Peirong Liu, Yueh Lee, Stephen Aylward, Marc Niethammer. "Perfusion Imaging: An Advection Diffusion Approach". *IEEE Transactions on Medical Imaging (TMI)*, 2021. [paper]

Peirong Liu, Yueh Lee, Stephen Aylward, Marc Niethammer. "PIANO: Perfusion Imaging via Advection-diffusion". Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2020. (Oral - 5%, student travel award) [paper] Lin Tian, Connor Puett, Peirong Liu, Zhengyang Shen, Stephen Aylward, Yueh Lee, Marc Niethammer. "Fluid registration between lung CT and stationary chest tomosynthesis images". Medical Image Computing and Computer Assisted Intervention (MICCAI), 2020. [paper]

Peirong Liu, Zhengwang Wu, Gang Li, Pew-Thian Yap, Dinggang Shen. "Deep Modeling of Growth Trajectories for Longitudinal Prediction of Missing Infant Cortical Surfaces". Information Processing in Medical Imaging (IPMI), 2019. (Oral - 10%, IPMI scholarship) [paper]

Industry Experience

Computer Vision, Meta AI

New York, U.S.

Chapel Hill, U.S.

Aug 2018 – May 2023

Research Intern, Supervisor: Dr. Rui Wang and Dr. Ser-Nam Lim

May 2022 – Nov 2022

• Research on vision transformer based, open-vocabulary image and video object detection.

Computer Vision, Meta AI

New York, U.S.

Research Intern, Supervisor: Dr. Rui Wang and Dr. Ser-Nam Lim

May 2021 - Nov 2021

• Researched on self-supervised, neural-ODE-based general framework for multi-view motion transfer. [arXiv]

Research Experience

Department of Computer Science, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Chapel Hill, U.S.

Research assistant, Supervisor: Dr. Marc Niethammer

Jan 2019 – Present

- Research on PDE/Physics-informed solutions for transport time series, from optimization-based and deep-learning-based perspectives. [MICCAI'20 Oral, TMI, CVPR'21 Oral, CVPR'22 Oral]
- Build a PyTorch stochastic advection-diffusion PDE solver toolkit (in 2/3D), which can be used for numerical solutions, fluid simulation, or as a general module in deep learning frameworks.
- Create a 3D brain advection-diffusion pseudo dataset and simulator which integrates (1) brain vessel segmentation, blood flow estimation; (2) diffusion tensor estimation; (3) brain advection-diffusion transport simulation.

Biomedical Research Imaging Center, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

Chapel Hill, U.S.

Research assistant, Supervisors: Dr. Dinggang Shen and Dr. Pew-Thian Yap

Aug 2018 – Dec 2018

• Research on geometric deep learning for mesh-structured data. Proposed a spatio-temporal-aware graph convolution neural network (GCNN) for longitudinal prediction of infant cortical growth. [IPMI'19 Oral]

Department of Mathematics, Shanghai University

Shanghai, China.

Undergraduate researcher, Supervisor: Dr. Shihui Ying

Sep 2016 – Jun 2018

• Researched on Riemannian spaces of shapes via the diffeomorphism group representation.

MICCAI Student Travel Award, Lima	2020
IPMI Scholarship, Hong Kong	2019
Outstanding Graduate, Shanghai	2018
President's List, Shanghai University (the Highest honor, Top 10)	2017
National Scholarship, Shanghai University (Top 1%)	2017
Baogang Outstanding Student Award, Shanghai (Top 4)	2017
Finalist Winner, U.S. Mathematical Contest In Modeling (MCM) (36 out of 8843 teams)	2017
Third Prize, Shanghai Mathematics Competitions (Math Major)	2016
Top Grade Scholarship, Shanghai University (Top 3%)	2015, 2016, 2017
Outstanding Student, Shanghai University	2015, 2016, 2017
Academic Innovation & Leadership & Public Service Award, Shanghai University	2015, 2016, 2017

Professional Services

Editorial board of Artificial Intelligence in Radiology

Review editor of Frontiers in Radiology

Reviewer of ICCV'21, CVPR'22, ECCV'22, MICCAI'22

Skills

Honors

Computer: Python, MATLAB, C/C++, LATEX, HTML, JAVA, R, MS Office **Libraries & OS**: PyTorch, TensorFlow, ITK, Theano; Linux (Ubuntu), Mac OSX **Languages**:

- Mandarin (Native Proficiency)
- English (Full Professional Proficiency)
 - TOEFL: 112 (R-29, L-29, S-26, W-28), GRE: 327+4.5 (V-157, Q-170, AW-4.5)
 - Advanced-level English Interpretation Certificate (Same level as Test for English Majors-Band 8 (TEM-8) for students in English major)

Hobbies:

- Guzheng: Professional level-10 certificate ("Distinction"), Duke Music Ensemble member
- Piano; Keyboard; Climbing; Hiking; Running; Table tennis